# TOMAS MAIORINO

Senior Fullstack Software Engineer

tomasmaiorino@gmail.com





Motivated by big challenges, quality work and by constant self-improvement, I'm always doing my best to learn something new, to help the team to increase their knowledge and to find a better way to solve problems. Involved in software development and tech assignments since 2008, I have a great experience working on large projects in various segments as financial, retail, and e-commerce. I've consistently looked and developed the best solution possible for the existent problem by using both JavaSE and JavaEE and their many frameworks, databases, and applications servers. As a Full Stack Developer, I'm constantly finding the assertive way to achieve the required goal with agility and quality. Nowadays, I'm working with Spring boot, microservices, containers, rest APIs for the backend and Angular 4 on the frontend. I also have experience with Java 8, MongoDB, Redis, RabbitMQ, Redis. I'm used to dealing with the needs required for a high availability and fast performance applications and I'm great in finding and solving critical issues with a tight schedule.

#### **PROJECTS**

# **Ecommerce Integration**

Ecommerce

The company would change its e-commerce platform and the current catalog integration would not work properly with this new platform. New microservices were created to support catalog, price, and inventory integrations. The microservice would read the messages from the RabbitMQ, perform some validations, and send them to the e-commerce platform through the rest API. Responsible for all catalog integration working directly with the product owner and business team to understand the definition of the project and help them to find the best solution. Helped on the architecture definition and developed, tested the solution and was part of the entire development from the development to production. Supported the QA team to find the better approach for the automated tests creation.

#### Achievements.

- Delivered a fast, lightweight, and testable solution which reduced the time spent during the catalog, price and inventory integrations.
- Reduced time spent consuming messages on the price integration from 3 hours to 15 minutes after a cache implementation.
- Reduced from 4 hours to 10 minutes the time spent for the read messages on the price integration.

Recover Password Ecommerce

Some company's clients were having trouble to recover their password through the website, which increased the amount of call received by the call center in order to help them to log in on the website. To solve the problem we changed the recovery password workflow to a more common approach by send to the client a link where they could change their password and login automatically on the website.

### Achievements.

• The company reduced by 30% the amount of calls to its call center from clients which was not able to recover their password through the website.

# **Housing Loan Simulator**

Financial

Working on the development of microservices that are used by a mortgage lender of a finance company. Helping in the definition and development of architecture, working throughout development from development, testing to production. Building testable, fast and lightweight applications. Support less experienced developers and interact with the business team to understand their needs and build a better product.

# **Command Tips**

Open Source | Own project

A node/react application where you can find/remember your most used commands. Click here to take a look at the live application.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCES**

Senior Software Engineer Aubay | 01-2019 - Present

Working for big companies in Lisbon city. My roles and responsibilities are.

- Discuss and understand the clients' need in order to improve their results and achieve its goals by building great systems or new feature using new technologies and development methodologies.
- Develop and maintain rest api's using Microservices, Spring Boot, Java 8, Rest Api's, SOAP webservices, JUnit, Mockito, RestAssured(integration tests), Cucumber, Jenkins, Docker, Git, Oracle, Jira.
- Maintain and work on new features related to the frontend's application.

Senior Software Engineer Compasso | 2017 - 2019

Worked for a big brazilians ecommerce in Sao Paulo. My roles and responsibilities included.

- Maintenance an internal application using Spring boot, Java 8, Angular 2, Webservices Rest, Soap Webservices for the catalog
- Responsible for the catalog integration between the Oracle Cloud Commerce and the clients catalog management tool using Spring Boot, Java 8, Webservices Rest, RabbitMQ, Docker, Kubernetes, Jira, JUnit, Mockito, Mongo, Redis, Maven and Jenkins. Helped on the architecture definition and which technologies to use.
- Develop and maintain rest api's using Microservices, Spring Boot, Java, Java EE, JUnit, Mockito, Gradle, Idap and Weblogic. Maintain the frontend application which interacts with the rest apis using Angular 2 and Angular material.
- Isolate and rectify issues in production through the analyses of applications' source code (Java 7), systems transactions' logs (Ecommerce and OSB) and thread dumps by using the following tools (Splunk, Dynatrace, Eclipse, Sql developer).
- Generate reports through complex queries and scripts (Oracle 11) to help the business team to check the impact of some issues in production in order to proactively mitigating either any financial impact or client experience

#### **Senior Fullstack Software Engineer**

Labdoor | 2017 - 2017

Worked on the website maintenance, bug fixes and developed new features. Developed, tested the solutions and was part of the entire development cycle, from the development to production.

## **Senior Software Developer**

Netshoes | 2015 - 2017

Developed new feature, bug fixes. I worked directly with the product owner and business team to understand the definition of the project. I developed, tested the solution and was part of the entire development cycle, from the development to production.

#### **SKILLS**

# Technical

JavaSE 8+, Angular 2, Spring Boot/Spring Data/Spring Transactions, PostgreSQL/MySQL/Oracle, RabbitMQ/ActiveMQ, Mongo/Redis, Object-oriented design, JMeter, GIT, JIRA/Bitbucket/JENKINS/DBeaver, Docker/Kubernetes, Unit and Integration tests/WireMock/Mockito, Design and implement database structures

## **Professional**

Team player, Focus, Strong problem solver, Good time management

# **EDUCATION**

(Associate Degree) Analysis and development of Systems UMESP 2007 - 2009

#### CERTIFICATION

Sun Certified Programmer for the Java 2 Platform, Standard Edition 5.0, 2009.



